

#### MASTER'S CANDIDATE, APPLIED CRYPTOGRAPHY

□ on request | ■ elem0@protonmail.com | ♠ eleanorm.info | 回 eleanor-em

### Summary\_

I am a recently-graduated Master of Science (Computer Science) student at the University of Melbourne, where I researched applied cryptography with Vanessa Teague. I have been a programmer for years, and am passionate about education, security, and privacy. Research interests include zero-knowledge proofs, post-quantum cryptography, and multiparty computation. This year I am due to begin my PhD in theoretical cryptography at FTH Zürich with Ueli Maurer.

#### Education

University of Melbourne Victoria, Australia

M.Sc. (Computer Science) (with Distinction) 2019-2020

B.Sc. (Mathematical Physics) 2015-2018

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATICS 2015-2018

## **Experience**

University of Melbourne Victoria, Australia

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jul 2019 - Present

Working with Prof. Shanika Karunasekera to develop and deploy RAPID, a large distributed cloud-based system for data collection and analytics.
The project allows large volumes of data (e.g. from social media) to be categorised by topic and analysed for patterns.

- Responsibilities include finding and fixing issues, as well as developing new features and system monitoring scripts.
- Assisted the security research group with grant applications.
- Working with Dr Olya Ohrimenko on attacks against differentially private mechanism implementations.

University of Melbourne Victoria, Australia

HEAD TUTOR Jul 2016 - Dec 2020

- Managed the tutoring team for a core subject (Object-Oriented Software Development) with hundreds of students, liaising between students, tutors, and lecturers.
- Developed major assignments for students, including specifications, marking criteria, and testing methodology.
- Delivered one to two lectures per semester on software tools and alternative paradigms while also teaching two to three tutorials per week.
- Tutor for various other subjects including Declarative Programming, Parallel & Multicore Computing, and Research Methods.

CSIRO (Clayton campus) Victoria, Australia

Casual IT Officer Apr 2016-Apr 2017

- · Worked with meterologists to create interactive data visualisation tools for hurricane data.
- Wrote software to process large volumes of unstructured data and extract meaningful information.
- Used augmented reality to work with new data visualisation methods.

### **Publications**

Eleanor McMurtry, Olivier Pereira, Vanessa Teague. When is a test not a proof? ESORICS (2020).

Eleanor McMurtry, Xavier Boyen, Chris Culnane, Kristian Gjøsteen, Thomas Haines, Ronald Rivest, Peter Ryan, Vanessa Teague. **Verifiable Remote Voting with Paper Assurance.** *In Submission.* 

Chris Culnane, Eleanor McMurtry, Robert Merkel, Vanessa Teague. Tracing the challenges of COVIDSafe. Blog post.

#### Honors & Awards\_

Best Technology, Codebrew Hackathon
Student Registration Grant, IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy
California, U.S.A.

2017 **Excellence in Tutoring Award**, School of Computing & Information Systems, Uni. of Melbourne *Victoria, Australia* 

#### Presentation

**CSides**Canberra, Australia

KER June 2020

· Presented an introduction to cryptography and formal notions of security.

JANUARY 5, 2021 ELEANOR MCMURTRY · CV

Speaker July 2020

• Presented an in-depth exploration of the COVIDSafe mobile app, focusing on the root causes of the issues with its application security.

### **Projects**

#### **Cryptid & PaperVote**

University of Melbourne 2019-2020

• Cryptid (https://github.com/eleanor-em/cryptid) is a threshold ElGamal implementation in Rust, over Curve25519. It also implements various zero-knowledge proofs, including a shuffle proof based on that in Verificatum.

- PaperVote (https://github.com/eleanor-em/papervote/) is an implementation of a verifiable voting protocol using Cryptid, based around augmenting postal voting techniques.
- This project is related to Master's work and the paper "Verifiable Remote Voting with Paper Assurance".

# Languages & Frameworks

I am able to work in a wide variety of technical environments including:

- C
- C++
- C#
- Java

- JavaScript
- Node.js
- React
- Python

- · Linux & Bash
- Rust
- Haskell
- CUDA